Egle Strockyte Product Design

egle.strockyte@gmail.com 1 (323) 504-1778 | egle.design

PROFILE

I'm a product design leader based in Los Angeles, and I've spent over 10 years working in a variety of settings, from early-stage startups to established companies and digital agencies.

I'm experienced with leading teams and designing intuitive digital products that drive both business success and positive change in people's lives.

Most recently, Product Design Manager at Bird. Previously, at Edenspiekermann and The Economist.

SKILLS

Product Design Information Architecture User Research & Testing Prototyping People Management Art Direction

EDUCATION

Master of Arts, Publishing (2010) University of the Arts London, LCC

Bachelor of Arts, Journalism and Media & Culture Studies (2009) Kingston University, London

Fine Arts Diploma (2005) Siauliai Art School, Lithuania

EXPERIENCE

Product Design Manager Lead Product Designer

2019 - present

As the Lead Product Designer at Bird, I designed new product features for the core rider app that spanned across key areas such as Rider Experience, Growth, Payments, and Compliance. Subsequently, as a Product Design Manager, I took on the responsibility of leading a team of talented designers who tackled multiple products, ranging from the Bird rider app and the Bird fleet manager app to internal servicing tools and new products for Bird partners.

UX Design Director, Edenspiekermann

2016 - 2019

I designed digital product experiences for brands in automotive, technology, government, publishing and finance. In my position as a UX Design Director, I owned and guided my team's design processes, methodologies and activities from concept through to finished product. I enjoyed coaching my team through challenges as much as being a hands-on member of the team at all stages of the project.

Product Designer, The Economist

2015 - 2016

I helped to create the new digital home of The Economist.
I meaningfully participated in the publication's new website ideating, prototyping, and development process, working with a large globally distributed stakeholders team.

Designer, Global Trade Review (GTR)

2012 - 2015

I planned and led GTR's digital rebrand. Designed and shipped the new responsive company's website alongside the email newsletters and confirmation emails. I played key role in liaison with numerous teams including web developers, editorial and marketing.

Freelance Designer

2011 - 2012

Worked on various web and print design projects for different clients. Design work mainly included responsive website mock-ups, client reports and presentations, posters and, also, physical product design.